micksgarage.com 2014-09-23

# MicksGarage - Privacy and Security

Introduction  
Types of Information Collected  
Purposes For Which We Hold Your Information  
Cookies  
Disclosure of Information to Third Parties  
Sale of Business  
Security  
Updating, Verifying and Deleting Personal Data  
Changes to the Web Site Privacy Policy  

### Introduction

We at MicksGarage respect your right to privacy and comply with our obligations under the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2002. The purpose of this Web Site Privacy Policy is to outline how we deal with any personal data you provide to us while visiting this web site. 

By visiting this web site, you are accepting the terms of this Web Site Privacy Policy. If you do not agree or are not comfortable with any policy described in this privacy statement, your only remedy is to discontinue use of the MicksGarage site. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. Your continued use of any portion of the MicksGarage Web site following notification or posting of such changes will constitute your acceptance of those changes. Any external links to other web sites are clearly identifiable as such, and we are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these other web sites. 

Back to top

### Types of Information Collected

We retain two types of information: 

**Personal Data** This is data that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you and may include your name, address, email address, user IP addresses in circumstances where they have not been deleted, clipped or anonymised, telephone number, and billing and credit card information. Such information is only collected from you if you voluntarily submit it to us. 

Please note all credit card or other payment information is transmitted using SSL encryption. [All payment information details, including credit card numbers and bank details, are permanently deleted from our servers when the payment has been processed. 

**Non-Personal Data** Like most web sites, we may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you use the Internet. When you visit a particular Web page in MicksGarage Web site, our servers log your IP address. 

Back to top

### Purposes For Which We Hold Your Information

##### Non-Personal Data

We use the Non-Personal Data gathered from visitors to our web site in an aggregate form to get a better understanding of where our visitors come from and to help us better design and organise our web site. 

##### Personal Data

We will process any Personal Data you provide to us for the following purposes: 

  1. to provide you with the goods or services you have ordered;
  2. to contact you if required in connection with your order or to respond to any communications you might send to us;
  3. to send you the MicksGarage Newsletter where you have opted in to receive such information

Back to top

### Cookies

This web site uses "cookie" technology. A cookie is a little piece of text stored by the browser on your computer, at the request of our server. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your personal preferences so you do not have to re-enter them each time you connect to our web site – our cookies are not available to other web sites. No personal information is recorded, and the cookie is automatically deleted when you log out or close your browser. You are always free to decline our cookies, if your browser permits, or to ask your browser to indicate when a cookie is being sent. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion. Note that if you decline our cookies or ask for notification each time a cookie is being sent, this may affect your ease of use of this web site. 

Back to top

### Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

We may provide Non-Personal Data to third parties, where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our web site. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our web site, the demographic breakdown of our community users of our web site, or the activities that visitors to our web site engage in while on our web site. The third parties to whom we may provide this information may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising services (including web site tracking services), commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties. 

We will not disclose your Personal Data to third parties unless you have consented to this disclosure. 

Back to top

### Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your Personal Data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of the Web Site Privacy Policy and provided that the third party only uses your Personal Data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out. 

Back to top

### Security

Your Personal Data is held on secure servers hosted by [SunGard](http://www.sungardas.ie/ "SunGard"). 

MicksGarage.com understand that you're concerned about the security and privacy of your online transactions. This is why we use GoDaddy SSL to ensure that your valuable data, such as credit card details, are encrypted when you interact with our site. 

We employ state-of-the-art data encryption to ensure safe and secure transactions to our site. Your computer and ours agree to transpose whatever we are sending into an unintelligible hash of characters, using a technology called SSL. For example: 

3048 0241 00C9 18FA CF8D EB2D EFD5 FD37 89B9 E069 EA97 FC20 5E35 F577 EE31 C4FB C6E4 4811 7D86 BC8F BAFA 362F 922B F01B 2F40 C744 2654 C0DD 2881 D673 CA2B 4003 C266 E2CD CB02 0301 0001

Without the information on your computer or ours, no one can understand our encrypted communication. For your safety, please expect anyone who communicates confidential information with you on the Internet to use encryption, the way we do. 

Secure Sockets Layer, SSL, is the security technology for encrypting a link between a web server and a browser. All data passed between our web server and your browser remains private and secure. 

Whenever you communicate with us on secure sections of micksgarage.com you'll notice that http:// is replaced by https:// (The 's' stands for 'Secure'). 

To generate an encrypted SSL transmission, a web server requires an SSL Certificate. Checking a website's certificate is good practice that helps you avoid spoof websites, sometimes called "phishing" sites. To check the certificate, click on the padlock. Your browser will show you the name of the owner of the certificate. This name should match the name of the website operator. 

Our SSL certificates are issued by a leading certificate authority, GoDaddy. GoDaddy is Web Trust-compliant, meaning that their business practices and processes have been rigorously audited according to AICPA (American Institute of Certified Public Accountants) guidelines by an independent approved auditor (Ernst & Young). 

GoDaddy SSL certificates enable a high level of encryption. They also confirm that a company is a legally accountable organization. 

To receive a SSL Certificate from GoDaddy, we had to demonstrate to them that we are an existing business, along with our control over the domain you are visiting. When you shop online, you deserve to know who you are interacting with. 

Seeing a site with a GoDaddy SSL Certificate, confirms two essential factors: 

That you have a secure SSL (encrypted) link with this website   
That this website represents a real organization 

To find out more about SSL or GoDaddy, please visit www.GoDaddy.com 

Back to top

### Updating, Verifying and Deleting Personal Data

You may inform us of any changes in your Personal Data, and in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2002 we will update or delete your Personal Data accordingly. To find out what Personal Data we hold on you or to have your Personal Data updated, amended or removed from our database, please contact us via eMail at info@micksgarage.com or via phone on +44(0) 2476 998425 

Back to top

### Changes to the Web Site Privacy Policy

Any changes to this Web Site Privacy Policy will be posted on this web site so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any time we decide to use Personal Data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Web Site Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner. 

Back to top
